Guide to the Larry Spruch Papers MC.209
New York University Archives
- Series V: Research, 1949-2004
  Series V contains materials generated by Larry Spruch and his collaborators while conducting and publishing research in theoretical particle physics and astrophysics. It is divided into four subseries. Subseries A: Published contains examples of Spruch's and his collaborators' work in its final, published format, usually as reprints or preprints. Drafts and earlier versions of many of these materials are also included in Subseries B: Drafts and Unpublished Writings. Subseries C: Notes and Calculations contains the least formal documents in this series. It is largely composed of notes and calculations on various issues in physics, some of which reappear in more polished form in Subseries A and B. Many of the materials in Subseries C, in particular, may be obscure in meaning to researchers without extensive backgrounds in physics, as their contents are expressed mathematically rather than in grammatical English. Finally, Subseries D: Research Proposals and Contracts contains proposals and contracts for grants to fund research in which Larry Spruch participated. Most of the materials in the series concern funding from the National Science Foundation; however, the Army Research Office and the Office of Naval Research are also represented.
  - Subseries A: Published, 1950-2002
    - "On the Space Exchange Magnetic Moments of Light Nuclei," Larry Spruch, 1950 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Various reprints by Larry Spruch, 1950-1976 (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - "Interaction Moment Contributions to Magnetic Moments of Nuclei," Arnold Russek and Larry Spruch, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - "Interaction Contribution to Nuclear Isomerism," Larry Spruch and Aubey Rotenberg, 1952 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - "Theory of Reflection, Refraction, and Diffraction of Electromagnetic Waves," (NYU Division of Electromagnetic Research Progress Report No. 22), 1954 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - "On the Eigenvalues Which Give Upper and Lower Bounds on Scattering Phases," Larry Spruch, 1956 (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - "Bounds on Scattering Phase Shifts," Larry Spruch, 1957 (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - "Low Energy Scattering by a Compound System: Positrons on Hydrogen," Larry Spurch and Leonard Rosenberg, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - "Bounds on the Elements of the Equivalent Network for Scattering in Waveguides," Larry Spruch and Ralph Bartram, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 9)
    - "Upper Bounds on Scattering Lengths When Composite Bound States Exist," L. Rosenberg, L. Spruch, and T. F. O'Malley, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 10)
    - "Upper Bounds on Scattering Lengths for Static Potentials," Larry Spruch and Leonard Rosenberg, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 11)
    - "Upper Bounds on Electron-Atomic Hydrogen Scattering Lengths," Leonard Rosenberg, Larry Spruch, and Thomas F. O'Malley, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 12)
    - "Bounds on Scattering Phase Shifts for Compound Systems," Leonard Rosenberg and Larry Spruch, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 13)
    - "Bounds on Scattering Phase Shifts: Static Central Potentials," Leonard Rosenberg and Larry Spruch, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 14)
    - "Upper Bound on the Neutron-Deuteron Doublet Scattering Length," Larry Spruch and Leonard Rosenberg, 1960 (Box 28, Folder 15)
    - Various publications by Spruch and colleagues on long-range potentials, 1960-1964 (Box 28, Folder 16)
    - Various reprints by Spruch on Modified Effective Range Theory, 1960-1971, 1980-1981 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - "Modification of Effective Range Theory in the Presence of a Long-Range (1/r4) Potential," Thomas F. O'Malley, Larry Spruch, and Leonard Rosenberg, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 18)
    - "Bounds on Elements of the S Matrix for Elastic Scattering: One Dimensional Scattering," Ralph Bartram and Larry Spruch, 1961 (Box 28, Folder 19)
    - "Minimum Principles in Scattering Theory," Larry Spruch, 1962 (Box 28, Folder 20)
    - "Hartree-Fock calculations of the ratio of bound-state to continuum beta decay of 187Re, the chronometric partner of 187Os", Zonghua Chen, Leonard Rosenberg, and Larry Spruch, 1962-1987 (Box 28, Folder 21)
    - "Bounds on Multichannel Scattering Parameters," Yukap Hahn, Thomas F. O'Malley, and Larry Spruch, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 22)
    - "Variational principles and minimum principles in scattering theory," Larry Spruch, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 23)
    - "Necessary Conditions for the Existence of Bound States," Larry Spruch, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 24)
    - "Necessary Conditions for the Existence of Bound States," with corrections, Larry Spruch, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 25)
    - "Notes on variational principles, variational bounds, and the few nucleon problem," Larry Spruch, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 26)
    - "Improved Minimum Principle for Multichannel Scattering," Yukap Hahn, Thomas F. O'Malley, and Larry Spruch, 1964 (Box 28, Folder 27)
    - "Coulombic Modified Effective-Range Theory for Long-Range Effective Potentials," R. Oppenheim Berger and Larry Spruch, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 28)
    - "Minimum-Principle Calculation of the Positron-Hydrogen s-wave Phase Shift," Yukap Hahn and Larry Spruch, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 29)
    - "Higher Partial Waves in Positron-Hydrogen Scattering," Chemia J. Kleinman, Yukap Hahn, and Larry Spruch, 1965 (Box 28, Folder 30)
    - "Relativistic versus nonrelativistic scattering of slow electrons," Larry Spruch, 1966 (Box 28, Folder 31)
    - "Relativistic Versus Nonrelativistic Scattering of Slow Electrons," Larry Spruch, 1966-1967 (Box 28, Folder 32)
    - "Remarks on variational bounds in scattering theory," Yukap Hahn and Larry Spruch, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 1)
    - "Variational Lower Bounds on Electron Hydrogen s-Wave Phase Shifts," I. Aronson, Yukap Hahn, Paul M. Henry, Chemia J. Kleinman, and Larry Spruch, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 2)
    - "Bounds on Cross Sections," Larry Spruch, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - "Static Green's Function for Elastic Electron-Hydrogen Scattering and Resonances," I. Aronson, Yukap Hahn, Paul M. Henry, Chemia J. Kleinman, and Larry Spruch, 1967 (Box 29, Folder 4)
    - "Variational Upper and Lower Bounds on Transitions Amplitudes," Larry Spruch, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    - "Dominant Nonadiabatic Contribution to the Long-Range Electron-Atom Interaction," Chemia J. Kleinman, Yukap Hahn, and Larry Spruch, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 6)
    - "Tables of Coefficients to Determine the Long-Range Contributions to Low-Energy Electron-Atom Scattering," R. Oppenheim Berger, H. B. Snodgrass, and Larry Spruch, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - "Feynman Path Integrals and Scattering Theory," Donald Gelman and Larry Spruch, 1969 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - "Low-Energy Scattering by Long-Range Potentials," Otto Hinckelmann and Larry Spruch, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - "Magnetic Field Effects on the Outermost Crusts of Pulsars," R. O. Mueller, A. R. P. Rau, and Larry Spruch, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 10)
    - "Statistical model of atoms in intense magnetic fields," R. O. Mueller, A. R. P. Rau, and Larry Spruch, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 11)
    - "Magnetic Fields Effects on the Outermost Crusts of Pulsars," R. O. Mueller, A. R. P. Rau, and Larry Spruch, 1971 (Box 29, Folder 12)
    - "Identities Related to Variational Principles," Edard Gerjuoy, A. R. P. Rau, and Larry Spruch, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 13)
    - "Simple Atomic Model and its Associated Wave Function," R. O. Mueller, A. R. P. Rau, and Larry Spruch, 1973 (Box 29, Folder 14)
    - "Simple model and wave function for atoms in intense magnetic fields," A. R. P. Rau, R. O. Mueller, and Larry Spruch, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 15)
    - "Lowest energy levels of H-, He, and Li+ in intense magnetic fields," R. O. Mueller, A. R. P. Rau, and Larry Spruch, 1975 (Box 29, Folder 16)
    - "Energy levels of hydrogen in magnetic fields of arbitrary strength," A. R. P. Rau and Larry Spruch, 1976 (Box 29, Folder 17)
    - Various reprints by Spruch, 1976-1978 (Box 29, Folder 18)
    - "Retardation effects on high Rydberg states: A retarded R -5 polarization potential," Edward J. Kelsey and Larry Spruch", 1978 (Box 29, Folder 19)
    - "Vacuum fluctuation and retardation effects on long-range potentials," Larry Spruch and Edward J. Kelsey, 1978 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Various reprints by Spruch, 1978, 1983-1985 (Box 29, Folder 20)
    - "Mechanisms for charge transfer (or for the capture of any light particle) at asymptotically high velocities," Robin Shakeshaft and Larry Spruch, 1979, 1983 (Box 29, Folder 21)
    - Publications by Spruch, sent to the NYU Executive Council, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 22)
    - "Large momentum transfer limit of some matrix elements," J. M. Wadehra and Larry Spruch, 1980 (Box 29, Folder 23)
    - "A unified formulation of the construction of variational principles," E. Gerjuoy, A. R. P. Rau, and Larry Spruch, 1983 (Box 29, Folder 24)
    - "Angular-distribution peak at 60° in electron capture from a heavy atom by a fast light ion" and "Simple heuristic derivation of some charge-transfer probabilities at asymptotically high incident velocities," Larry Spruch and Robin Shakeshaft, 1984 (Box 29, Folder 25)
    - "Nodal structure of zero-energy wave functions: New approach to Levinson's theorem," and Nodal structure adn phase shifts of zero-incident-energy wave functions: Multiparticle single-channel scattering," Z. R. Iwinski, Leonard Rosenberg, and Larry Spruch, 1985-1986 (Box 29, Folder 26)
    - "Retarded, or Casimir, long-range potentials", 1986 (Box 29, Folder 27)
    - "Extremum principles for the determination of relativistic bound-state energies," Leonard Rosenberg and Larry Spruch, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 28)
    - Levinson theorem publications by Larry Spruch and Leonard Rosenberg, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 29)
    - "Relative contributions of the electron-electron and electron-nuclear interactions to the ground-state energy of a neutral atom," Zonghua Chen and Larry Spruch, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 30)
    - "Retardation (Casimir) effects on high and not so high Rydberg states of helium," James F. Babb and Larry Spruch, 1987 (Box 29, Folder 31)
    - "Effect of infrared radiation on the threshold behavior of scattering (and decay) processes," Ajaya K. Mohanty, Leonard Rosenberg, and Larry Spruch, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 32)
    - "Evaluation of retardation energy shifts in a Rudberg helium atom," James F. Babb and Larry Spruch, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 33)
    - "Retarded (Casimir) effect for a multielectron core system and a Rydberg electron," James F. Babb and Larry Spruch, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 34)
    - "Atomic screening effects on electron-neutrino angular correlation and β-decay asymmetry in allowed transitions," Zonghua Chen, Walter R. Johnson, and Larry Spruch, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 35)
    - "First Experiments with the Heidelberg Test Storage Ring TSR," D. Habs et al. (including Larry Spruch), 1989 (Box 29, Folder 36)
    - "On the β-decay of 187Re: an interface of atomic and nuclear physics and of cosmochronology," Zonghua Chen, Leonard Rosenberg, and Larry Spruch, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 37)
    - "Lower bounds on the ground-state energy and necessary conditions for the existence of bound states: The potential problem," Zonghua Chen and Larry Spruch, 1990 (Box 29, Folder 38)
    - "Semiclassical estimation of the radiative mean lifetimes of hydrogenlike states," Hermann Marxer and Larry Spruch, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 39)
    - "Pedagogic notes on Thomas-Fermi theory (and on some improvements): atoms, stars, and the stability of bulk matter," Larry Spruch, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 40)
    - "Semiclassical estimation of the radiative mean lifetime of an electron in a (Landau) bound state in a uniform magnetic field," Hermann Marxer and Larry Spruch, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 41)
    - "Retardation (Casimir) energy shifts for Rydberg helium-like low Z ions," James F. Babb, Dietrich Habs, Larry Spruch, and Andreas Wolf, 1992 (Box 29, Folder 42)
    - "Elementary approximate derivations of some retarded Casimir interactions involving one or two dielectric walls," Larry Spruch and Yoel Tikochinsky, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 43)
    - "An Overview of Long-Range Casimir Interactions," Larry Spruch - chapter 1 of Long-Range Casimir Forces: Theory and Recent Experiments in Atomic Systems, eds. Frank S. Levin and David A. Micha (New York: Plenum Press) 1993. (Box 29, Folder 44)
    - "Retarded Casimir interaction in the asymptotic domain of an electron and a dielectric wall," Yoel Tikochinsky and Larry Spruch, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 45)
    - "Retarded electric and magnetic Casimir interaction of a polarizable system and a dielectric permeable wall," Yoel Tikochinsky and Larry Spruch, 1993 (Box 29, Folder 46)
    - "Temperature-induced transition rates for some hydrogenic states," Fei Zhou and Larry Spruch, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 47)
    - "A simple derivation of the asymptotic interactions of a pair of finite systems," Larry Spruch, James F. Babb, and Fei Zhou, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 48)
    - "Retardation (or Casimir) potential for the Rydberg hydrogen molecule," James F. Babb and Larry Spruch, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 49)
    - van der Waals and retardation (Casimir) interactions of an electron or an atom with multi-layered walls," Fei Zhou and Larry Spruch, 1995 (Box 29, Folder 50)
    - "Absolute determination of zero-energy phase shifts for multiparticle single-channel scattering: Generalized Levinson theorem," Leonard Rosenberg and Larry Spruch, 1995-1996 (Box 29, Folder 51)
    - "Generalized Levinson theorem: Applications to electron-atom scattering," Leonard Rosenberg and Larry Spruch, 1996 (Box 29, Folder 52)
    - "Long-Range (Casimir) Interactions," Larry Spruch, 1996 (Box 29, Folder 53)
    - "Physics adores a vacuum," Larry Spruch, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 54)
    - "Near-degeneracy effect on energy shifts in some high charged few-electron Rydberg ions," Steffen D. Frischat, Thomas Schüßler, Larry Spruch, and Andreas Wolf, 1997 (Box 29, Folder 55)
    - "Infinity-free semiclassical evaluation of Casimir effects," Martin Schaden and Larry Spruch, 1998 (Box 29, Folder 56)
    - "Focusing virtual photons: Casimir energies for some pairs of conductors," Martin Schaden and Larry Spruch, 1999 (Box 29, Folder 57)
    - "Casimir Effects and Lamb Shifts," Larry Spruch and M. Schaden, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 58)
    - "Semiclassical evaluation of some Casimir effects," M. Schaden and L. Spruch, 2000 (Box 29, Folder 59)
    - "Semiclassical Casimir energies at finite temperature," Martin Schaden and Larry Spruch, 2002 (Box 29, Folder 60)
    - "Classical Casimir effect: The interaction of ideal parallel walls at a finite temperature," Martin Schaden and Larry Spruch, 2002 (Box 29, Folder 61)
    - "Upper Bounds on Scattering Lengths," Larry Spruch and Leonard Rosenberg, undated (Box 29, Folder 62)
    - "Calculation of the s-wave phase shift for positron hydrogen scattering by a minimum principle," Yukap Hahn, Thomas F. O'Malley, and Larry Spruch, undated (Box 29, Folder 63)
    - "A report on some few-body problems in atomic physics," Larry Spruch, undated (Box 29, Folder 64)
  - Subseries B: Drafts and Unpublished Writings, 1964-2004
    - "Necessary Conditions for the Existence of Bound States," Larry Spruch, 1964 (Box 30, Folder 1)
    - "Outline of Some Research at NYU", 1966 (Box 30, Folder 2)
    - "The Adiabatic Approximation and Necessary Conditions for the Existence of Bound States," F. H. Gertler, H. B. Snodgrass, and Larry Spruch, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 3)
    - Review of and problems from Rodberg and Thaler, Introduction to the Quantum Theory of Scattering, 1967 (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - "On the Time Translation Operator U(t,t0) for Time-Dependent Potentials," L. Spruch and R. Snider, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - Figures for bounds on cross sections, published in The Physics of Electronic and Atomic Collisions, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - "Tables of the Coefficients which Determine the Long-Range Contributions to Electron-Atom Scattering," R. Oppenheim Berger, H. B. Snodgrass, and Larry Spruch, 1968-1969 (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - Larry Spruch bibliography, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Larry Spruch bibliography, 1970, 1978 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Manuscript on variational principles for 3-body breakup scattering by Larry Spruch, Leonard Rosenberg, and Michael Lieber, 1971 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - "Attractive Alternative to the Thomas-Fermi Model of the Atom", 1971-1973 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - "Useful Extremum Principle for the Variational Calculation of Matrix Elements," Edward Gerjuoy, A. R. P. Rau, L. Rosenberg, and Larry Spruch, 1972-1973 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - "Useful Extremum Principle for the Variational Calculation of Matrix Elements," Edward Gerjuoy, A. R. P. Rau, L. Rosenberg, and Larry Spruch (revised), 1973 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - "A Note on the Time Translation Operator U(t,t0) for Time-Dependent Potentials," R. Shakeshaft, R. F. Snider, and L. Spruch, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - "Adiabatic Approximation and the Other (Lower) Bound on the Scattering Length," Yukap Hahn and Larry Spruch, 1973 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - "Adiabatic Approximation and Variational Lower Bounds on Binding Energies and Phase Shifts", 1973 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - "The Thomas-Fermi theory and some of its ramifications" manuscript and related materials, 1975-1981 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - Untitled manuscript with corrections, for Physical Review Letters, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - "Nonsingular Variational Principle for the Scattering Length for the Target Wave Function Imprecisely Known," Larry Spruch and Leonard Rosenberg, 1978-1979 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - "e- wall manuscript," Larry Spruch, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - "Mechanisms for charge transfer (or for the capture of any light particle) at asymptotically high impact velocities," Robin Shakeshaft and Larry Spruch, 1979 (Box 30, Folder 21)
    - "Large momentum transfer limit of some matrix elements," J. M. Wadehra and Larry Spruch, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Jogindra Wadehra's corrections to "Large momentum transfer limit of some matrix elements" manuscript, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Manuscript draft on Modified Effective Range Theory, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - "Electron-Atom Scattering: The State of the Theory," Larry Spruch, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - "The Thomas-Fermi theory and some of its ramifications," Larry Spruch, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - "Pedagogic notes on some ramifications of Thomas-Fermi theory: atoms, stars and matter," Larry Spruch, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Figures for Physical Review paper with Robin Shakeshaft, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - The no-binding theorem for molecules" manuscript fragment and notes, 1980 (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Biography for Contemporary Authors, Who's Who, 1980-1983, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - "Comparison of non-relativistic (Schrödinger or Pauli-Schrödinger) energies with relativistic (Dirac or Klein-Gordon) energies for the nth bound state", 1982 (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - "Electron capture from the outer shells of a heavy atom," Larry Spruch and Robin Shakeshaft, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - "Long range (retarded, Casimir) interactions in atomic systems," Larry Spruch and James F. Babb, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 33)
    - Uncorrected manuscripts for Thomas-Fermi review article with Shakeshaft and Rau, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - "A unified formulation of the construction of variational principles," E. Gerjuoy, A. R. P. Rau, and Larry Spruch (galleys), 1983 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Fei Zhou and Larry Spruch, "van der Waals and retardation (Casimir) interactions of an electron or atom with multi-layered walls", 1984 (Box 30, Folder 35)
    - Typed material for Thomas-Fermi review papers: Robin Shakeshaft and Ravi Rau, with Spruch's notes, 1984 (Box 30, Folder 36)
    - Citation index, Larry Spruch, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 37)
    - "Extremum principles for the determination of relativistic ground-state energies," Larry Spruch, 1986, 1997 (Box 30, Folder 38)
    - "Reduced mass and retardation manuscript," Larry Spruch, 1987 (Box 30, Folder 39)
    - Spruch bibliography and "self-portrait", 1987 (Box 30, Folder 40)
    - Problems for "Book", 1988 (Box 30, Folder 41)
    - Brookhaven National Laboratory Draft Feasibility Study for a National Atomic Physics Facility, 1988 (Box 30, Folder 42)
    - "The no-binding theorem for molecules" manuscript and notes, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 43)
    - "Pedagogic notes on some ramifications of Thomas-Fermi theory: atoms, stars, and bulk matter," Larry Spruch, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 44)
    - "Flexible poles as a 'simple machine' and as a possible tool of the Egyptian pyramid builders," John Cunningham and Larry Spruch, 1990-1991 (Box 30, Folder 45)
    - Egyptian pyramids construction manuscript fragments, 1990-1991 (Box 30, Folder 46)
    - Spruch bibliography, 1991-1994 (Box 30, Folder 47)
    - "The retardation (or Casimir) potential for the Rydberg hydrogen molecule," James F. Babb and Larry Spruch, 1992-1994 (Box 30, Folder 48)
    - "Pedagogic notes on some ramifications of Thomas-Fermi theory: atoms, stars, and bulk matter" galleys, 1991 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Larry Spruch curriculum vitae, 1992 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Collaboration with John Cunningham: "Flexible poles as a 'simple machine' and as a possible tool of the Egyptian pyramid builders", 1992-1993 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - "A simple derivation of the asymptotic Sacimir interaction of a pair of finite systems," Larry Spruch, James F. Babb, and Fei Zhou, 1993 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - "An Overview of Long-Range Casimir Interactions," Larry Spruch - chapter 1 of Long-Range Casimir Forces: Theory and Recent Experiments in Atomic Systems, eds. Frank S. Levin and David A. Micha (New York: Plenum Press) 1993. (Galleys) (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Notes and draft fragments, Casimir potentials article with Fei Zhou, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - "Casimir energies and superluminal velocities," Massimo Porrati, Larry Spruch and Fei Zhou, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Electromagnetism problems with solutions, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - O+4 manuscript draft sections, 1995 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - "Nonadiabatic coefficients of long-range effective potentials and the Faraday effect," Carl Krauthauser, E. J. Robinson, L. Rosenberg, and Larry Spruch, 1995-1996 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - "Generalized Levinson theorem: Applications to electron-atom scattering," Leonard Rosenberg and Larry Spruch, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - "Absolute determination of zero-energy phase shifts for multiparticle single-channel scattering: a generalized Levinson theorem," Leonard Rosenberg and Larry Spruch, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - "Near-Degeneracy Effect on Polarization Energy Shifts in Some Highly Charged Few-Electron Rydberg Ions," Steffen D. Frischat, Thomas Schüßler, Larry Spruch, and Andreas Wolf, 1996 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - "Temperature-induced transition rates for some hydrogenic states," Fei Zhou and Larry Spruch, 1994 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Special issue of Comments on Atomic and Molecular Physics: Casimir Forces, 1999 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Bibliography of Spruch publications, compiled by Ben Bederson, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Draft text for Larry Spruch website, 2000 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Larry Spruch bibliography, 2001 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - Science Fiction: Aliens and Human Rights, 2001 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - "Non-physical singularities in some scattering, bound state, electrostatic, van der Waals, and Casimir problems," Larry Spruch, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - "Diffraction in the Semiclassical Approximation to Feynman's Path Integral Representation of the Green Function," Martin Schaden and Larry Spruch, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - "The Tax Law: A Layman's View," Larry Spruch, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - "Classical Casimir interactions at very high temperature of some simple systems," Larry Spruch, 2002 (Box 31, Folder 22)